Translated By The Community Of WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
Previously on
Suits...
What I want is to work
at Pearson Specter
and to keep seeing you.
Those two things are not
both gonna happen.
You've been here
for three months.
All you've done is hit singles,
and I need a goddamn home run.
- Jonathan, listen--
- I don't want to hear it.
Start making us
some real money.
A man like Walter Gillis
isn't gonna listen
to a guy like you,
offering to save him
with sunshine and rainbows.
Walter, I can't guarantee you
we'll win,
but I can guarantee you
that I will never sell you out.
All right,
I'm in.
You're talking
hostile takeover.
Gillis industries--
Logan, we have a conflict.
You're either with me
or against me.
That includes all $1 billion
of my business.
Get moving on drawing up a
tender offer for Logan Sanders.
Do you remember
when I told you
that I once had an affair
with a married man?
It was him.
You're up early.
So are you.
Well, I have to be.
You don't.
I was already awake.
Thinking.
About last night?
Look, Mike, I--
- it's okay.
I'm good.
You're good with me working
on the takeover with Logan?
Why do you not
seem to believe me?
Because you weren't good
last night.
Which was before this morning
when I realized that
that's work.
This isn't.
[Exhales deeply]
So as long as we don't let
that affect this...
We won't.
In that case, let's set
some in-home ground rules.
Obviously, the first--
Uh, respecting
each other's privacy.
Exactly.
The left-hand side of the desk
belongs
to the United Nation of Ross.
- You're not a nation.
- I have a flag.
[Scoffs] Fine.
As long as we agree
that any perusal of my phone
is considered a breach
of my borders.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I thought you liked it
when I breached your borders.
Mm, well, those are
different kind of borders.
In that case,
a breach is allowed.
- Allowed?
- Encouraged.
- Requested.
- Demanded.
Let's go make you
late for work.
Mm.
Jessica, I am telling you.
The S.E.C. is gonna send
Jeff Malone after us,
and nobody is better suited
to beat him down than--
you guessed it
because we all know that
this is better than this,
which will result in this,
which will also result
in this
and this
and this.
And what do I want in return?
Oh, you know what I want.
You've always known.
And after I win,
you'll not only be willing
to give it to me.
You're gonna be begging
Ha!
- Louis.
- B--not now.
- Louis, I have to talk to you.
How many times
have I told you?
Unless you have photoshopped
my head onto a dragon,
do not interrupt me
while I'm perfecting my pitch.
Your pitch doesn't need
to be perfect.
It needs to be now.
- Why?
- Malone is here.
- He's here?
- In the lobby.
And Jessica just asked
to see you.
Oh, out of my way.
Aren't--aren't you going
to bring your easel?
Oh, I don't need an easel
to kick this sucker's ass.
Jessica.
Jessica, I got your message,
and I just wanted to--
Louis, this is Jeff Malone.
Yeah, I know who he is.
He's with the S.E.C.
He was
until this morning.
We brought him over
because we have reason
to believe
they'll be coming after us.
Wait, what?
Jeff is
our newest senior partner.
He's going to be taking on
the S.E.C.
Because you suck.
And I wanted to introduce him
to you first
because you're a loser.
Who can get him up to speed
on Felton Securities.
Because you're never
going to be name partner.
And you're both experts
in finance.
Louis, I'm really looking
forward to working with you
on Felton Securities.
Yeah, me too.
You suck.
You're a loser.
Louis?
Is there something else?
No.
Nothing.
[Inhales sharply]
How long you been
working on that?
Two hours.
You know it's called
a brief, right?
You know
his name's Harvey, right?
You make
a compelling argument.
So I got your note.
What do you wanna talk about?
Um...
Logan Sanders.
What about him?
We sort of dated
a few years ago.
Wait, hang on.
Define "sort of."
- Definitely.
- Define "dated."
We had an affair
while he was married.
Holy shit.
I know.
And I--
Yes, you have
to tell Harvey.
Because, Rachel, if there's
two things that Harvey hates,
it's things being kept from him
and things being kept from him.
- I know.
- Then what am I doing here?
I don't know
how to tell him.
Quickly, because Logan's
gonna be here in an hour.
What?
And, Rach, it's less important
how you tell Harvey
than that you tell Harvey.
Go.
[Sighs]
Okay.
Hmm.
These are nice.
♪ See the money,
wanna stay for your meal ♪
♪ get another piece of pie
for your wife ♪
♪ everybody wanna know
how it feel ♪
♪ everybody wanna see
what it's like ♪
♪ living in a beehive
of your mind ♪
♪ Suits 4x02 ♪
Breakfast, Lunch and Dinner
Original Air Date on June 18, 2014
♪ all right
♪ all that time
imagine this ♪
♪ the greenback boogie
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
I was wondering all day
if you would be--
I can't do this.
What?
Rachel--
It's wrong.
Wrong?
You're the one who kissed me.
And I was wrong.
No, you weren't.
My whole life
I've done everything
that I was supposed to do,
and all it did
was make me miserable.
Ever since I met you...
I can't stop thinking about you,
and all I want to do--
Logan--
Logan, if we do this,
someone's gonna find out
at some point and then what?
I don't care.
[Whispering]
Okay.
Harvey, I need to tell you--
Rachel?
Logan.
Where's Harvey?
I don't know.
I'm early.
He doesn't like it
when people--
- What are you doing here?
- I'm Harvey's associate.
You did it.
You went to law school.
Not exactly.
I'm in law school.
Rachel, that's great.
I'm really proud of you.
I'm just gonna come back.
You came in here to tell him
about us, didn't you?
How'd you know?
It's all over your face.
- Logan--
- Please don't tell him.
I have to tell him.
Rachel...
Do you know
what people think
when a son
takes over his father's company?
That his father's proud
of him?
That he didn't earn it.
Which is why I'm not looking
to advertise the fact
that I once had an affair.
You're not advertising it.
You're disclosing it to counsel.
Okay, look,
you want the truth?
I'm not proud of the way I was
back then.
The way I treated Allison,
the way I treated you.
But I'm not that person
anymore,
and I don't want people
to think that I am.
And I understand that,
but I work for Harvey,
and I can't keep things from him
that he needs to know.
- He doesn't need to know this.
- Yes, he does.
Why is that?
Because I happen to live
with the man on the other side
of the takeover battle.
Oh, no.
You need some me time already?
It's not me time.
It's "I'm gonna kick
your ass" time.
I think we both know you only
kick ass after eating a hot dog.
I could be drinking a juice
box and still kick your ass.
I don't think so,
because I have this.
Just read it to me.
"Harvey Specter,
you are summoned to"--
You gotta be kidding me.
You're subpoenaing me?
Oh, yeah.
I filed a T.R.O.
I'm gonna block
your tender offer.
Bullshit, you are.
Well, we'll see what the judge
has to say.
Oh, right.
You got your hands full.
Here, let me get that for you.
There you go.
Hearing's at 2:00.
I'll see you then.
Oh, Harvey, the suit--
it's a little dated for court,
don't you think?
Did you get everything
settled with hr?
Yeah.
Corner office.
You really must like me.
[Chuckles]
Don't get too excited.
You know, the last two partners
that had this office
didn't survive the year.
Then it's a good thing
I'm much better than they were.
You don't even know
who they were.
That doesn't matter, Jessica.
I know who I am.
Me too--
cocky lawyer in a corner office
who hasn't done a thing
for me yet.
Yet.
By the way, I understand it's
tradition for the name partner
to welcome a new partner
with lunch.
Jeff, when I told you
that our relationship
is now purely professional,
I was serious.
Jessica, what's not
purely professional about lunch?
Unless you mean the sex
that will be following lunch?
Oh, you're not hearing me.
Oh, I'm hearing you.
I'm just ignoring you.
But I promise I won't be
ignoring you at lunch.
Cocky.
Harvey. Harvey, can I talk
to you for a minute?
Yeah, sure,
come on in.
I was actually hoping
that we could talk in my office.
What's the--
You're early.
- Did you...
- Oh, you two haven't met.
Rachel, Logan.
Logan, Rachel.
- I guess you didn't.
- Didn't what?
We actually have met before.
That's why I was trying
to find you.
- To tell me you met our client?
- No.
To tell you that we used to be
in a relationship together.
You looking
to get back together?
Both: No.
- Then I don't give a shit.
- Good.
Then we can move on to why
you didn't tell me that the guy
on the other side of this fight
used to be your associate.
- I was going to.
- When?
In 20 minutes, when you were
scheduled to be here.
Unfortunately,
I have to reschedule.
- Why?
- I have court.
Mike's alleging
I broke privilege.
- Did you?
- Yes, technically,
when I told you to move up
our timeline.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
W-wait a minute.
If you--if you broke privilege,
what are you gonna
tell the judge?
I don't know,
but until I think of something,
I'm going to confuse the shit
out of everyone I can.
That doesn't make any sense.
- It makes total sense.
- No, it doesn't, Your Honor.
All right, hold on.
Let me get this straight.
You work for him?
Worked. I was his associate.
Not the best associate,
Your Honor.
Is that relevant?
No, but I'd like it
on the record.
Well, it's on there now
whether we want it there or not.
And all I'm saying is, there's
no attorney-attorney privilege.
Finally, a fact.
An irrelevant fact,
because at the time
of the conflict,
I was his client.
Not the best client either.
Mr. Specter, shut up.
Now you're his client?
No, I was his client--
okay.
I was an associate
at Pearson Specter,
and then I left
to become an investment banker.
It's very confusing.
I'd dismiss the whole motion,
Your Honor.
I said, "shut up."
Are you an attorney
or an investment banker?
I'm an investment banker.
Then what the hell
are you doing in my chambers?
Acting as my own attorney.
And no matter how much he tries
to confuse the issue, he can't.
I told him I was going
after the same company he was,
and he used that knowledge
to move up his tender offer.
He waived conflict.
That doesn't apply
to privilege.
Bottom line is, he doesn't
have proof of anything.
I don't, but he does.
Unfortunately,
he can't force me to testify.
There's no precedent.
Fortunately, there is.
So go ahead, ask him
if he did what I'm saying.
Mr. Specter,
do I need to swear you in?
Give him the T.R.O.
You know,
I'll do more than that.
Not only can't your client make
a tender offer for 60 days,
they can't purchase any more
stock until then either.
I'm telling you,
we need to negotiate with him.
You mean pay him off?
Yes, that's exactly
what I mean.
Every day this drags on, it's
millions out of your pocket.
Well, from where I'm sitting,
all I can see is a lawyer
trying to distract me
from the fact
that this whole thing
is his fault.
If I didn't break privilege,
he might have locked
this whole thing up
before you knew
what hit you.
Fine.
We'll negotiate.
No, I'll negotiate.
No, not without me.
Do I need to draw you
a picture?
You, Mike, Rachel.
Harvey, I appreciate
your concern,
but this is my first deal, so
unless you're gonna pay him off
with your money,
I'm gonna be at that meeting.
What are you doing?
I'm writing in my diary.
Isn't that
what your dictaphone is for?
No, my dictaphone
is for my singular triumphs,
like when Harvey told me
I was the man,
and my diary is
for my most agonizing defeats,
such as when Jessica just told
me I'll never make name partner.
- Louis, she didn't say that.
- Well, she might as well have.
She just gave Malone
the corner office.
Oh, my God.
Yeah.
And what's more is
I think I agreed
to give him
Felton Securities.
Well, un-agree to it.
I can't.
I shook his hand.
The die is cast.
God damn it, Louis.
You know how this works.
First it's a case.
Then it's a client.
Before you know it, you're
on the 38th floor with Ted.
- Who's Ted?
- Exactly.
Holy shit.
What did I just do?
I'll tell you
what you're gonna do.
You're gonna stop writing
in that pussy diary,
and you're gonna show Jessica
you're the one
who should be sitting
in that corner office.
Ready the dictaphone.
We're gonna need it.
Hey. How are things
going Logan Sanders.
- You have no idea.
- Do I want to have an idea?
Not unless you want to hear
about how Mike Ross
is still
causing us trouble.
Nope.
You don't care about
Logan Sanders at all, do you?
No.
This isn't
a coincidental encounter, is it?
No, it is not.
You are having lunch
with Jeff Malone today.
Come on, Jessica.
You banged him.
The least you could do
is take him to lunch.
That is not funny.
Wait a second,
you want me to take him to lunch
because you banged him.
Harvey...
I want you to go ahead
and say "banged"
to my face one more time.
I'm not going to but not
because I'm scared of you.
Whatever lets you sleep
at night, white boy.
Donna, tell Paul Porter
he's meeting me for lunch.
When he gets there, tell them
to seat him with Jeff Malone.
Who's he not having
lunch with?
- Jessica.
- Oh, done.
Aren't you gonna ask me why?
She asked you to go
because she didn't want to.
You're sending Porter
because you don't want to,
but you didn't have the balls
to say no to her face.
Is that it?
The balls are debatable.
Balls are never debatable.
- Ah, hey there.
- Hey.
Louis, listen,
I just, um--
I just wanted to say
one more time
how much I'm really looking
forward to working with you.
Aww, well, I would just like
to say for the first time
that you will not be
working with me,
because I will not be giving you
my jock,
let alone my case.
Yeah.
Okay, I get it.
So you're the guy?
Yeah, I am the guy.
No, not that guy, Louis.
Definitely not that guy.
You're the guy in every office
who wants to piss
on the new guy, you know,
to mark your territory.
So why don't I just walk you on
down to my office?
I'm gonna let you get your
little piss on in my corner,
and then we can move on.
Oh, I've moved on.
I've set the deposition
for Todd Smith tomorrow.
You don't think
I know about that?
I don't give a shit
whether you know it or not.
It's my job to determine
whether Todd Smith is guilty.
And who do you actually think
is better at determining
whether a guy is guilty
of insider trading, Louis?
A career prosecutor
for the S.E.C.
or a monkey
in some Italian suit?
- [Chuckles] A monkey?
- Monkey.
Well, you're nothing
but a crowing cock.
And the last cock that walked
into my office
learned what
all the other cocks learned--
that I eat cock for breakfast,
lunch, and dinner.
Louis, you're gonna let me
in that deposition tomorrow
whether you like it or not.
Why, because you're gonna run
to Jessica?
No, simply because I'm gonna
tell everyone here in the office
that you said you eat cock for
breakfast, lunch, and dinner.
Yeah, that's right.
It's goddamn delicious.
Mmm! Mmm, mmm.
[Barks]
So what, you think
you can handle Todd Smith
better than me?
Well, let's just see.
Let's just see what you got.
Saw you scheduled a meeting
with Mike.
I assume that means you're going
to offer him a deal.
It could mean I'm going to
offer him a trip to Disneyland.
But it doesn't.
Of course not, he'd probably
want to wear mouse ears,
and then nobody wins.
You're welcome.
I didn't thank you.
Since you scheduled the meeting
when I'm at law school,
which you did to cut me out.
Did you get your name
on the wall since lunch?
No.
Then let's get
something straight.
I didn't set that meeting.
Donna did.
And if I didn't want you there,
I'd just tell you to your face.
So let me tell you now, you're
not going to that meeting.
Because you think
I can't handle it?
Because I'm not throwing
gasoline on a pile of matches
just to see what happens.
Now, if you're done
wasting my time,
you just gave me an idea.
You're welcome.
Harvey, what are you
doing here?
You said it yourself.
I never brought you a gift
when you moved in.
- Still don't see an orchid.
- Flowers die.
I thought I'd bring
something better.
Me...
Across the table from you.
- Where's your client?
- He doesn't need to be here.
This fight started
with you and me.
So let's you and me
settle it right now.
You mean you don't want him
here because you don't think
Logan Sanders and I
can be in the same room.
I don't think.
I know.
Harvey, I'm a grown man.
I can sit across the table
from somebody
who had a history with Rachel.
Maybe, but you both
have a brain and a dick,
and if you get in that room
together,
the brains aren't gonna be
leading that conversation.
Fine, you tell me
that you have the authority
to negotiate a deal,
and I'll negotiate.
But you can't
'cause you don't.
And I'm not gonna agree
to something here today
just to have Logan reject it
tomorrow.
So go home, get some sleep,
and then the three of us
will do this again
in the morning.
Look, here's the thing Todd
You're not actually our client.
Felton Securities is.
And it's my job to find out
if you're telling the truth.
Bullshit.
It's my job.
- Louis, I'm handling this.
- No, you're not.
If he doesn't stop lying to me,
I'm gonna cut him looser
than Jared's pants
after a Subway diet.
- I'm not lying to you.
- You took a tip.
All right, Todd, you took a tip,
used it for your client--
Yes, and now you're trying--
God damn it, Louis!
Listen, if you don't back
the hell off my interrogation,
I'm gonna pick
his scrawny ass up
and use him to beat
the shit out of you!
Stop it!
You think I don't know
what you're doing?
You're trying to rattle me.
- Uh-oh.
- What?
Uh, your vein.
- Here?
- It's bulging.
Just like mine did,
right before my heart attack.
- Louis, he's not gonna--
- What? Have a heart attack?
That was exactly my thought
ten seconds before I was slumped
on the courtroom floor.
Oh, wow,
it's just like Jenkins.
- Jenkins?
- No shit, Jenkins too?
He was sitting
right next to me, hand to God.
And, Louis, you should have
seen his wife and kids
at the funeral.
Funeral?
- Yeah, you have kids, Todd?
- Yeah, I have two kids.
Yeah, well, whether it's
a heart attack or prison time,
if you do not stop
lying to us,
they're never going to see
their father again.
Do you understand
what I just said?
You are never going to play
soccer with them--
Okay.
Okay, I am lying to you.
But please,
you gotta help me.
Well, we want to.
But, T-dog, you gotta be
straight up with your homies
if you want us
to have your back.
The truth is,
I'm germaphobic.
I have to wash my hands
throughout the day.
And they get dry--
I mean really dry--
so I have to put on
a lot of lotion.
And I know
this sounds ridiculous,
but my finger must have slipped
on the keyboard, and I--
I hit the wrong stock.
You're saying that you didn't
even mean to buy that stock?
Nope, but then
it skyrocketed,
and I wasn't gonna tell
everybody that I only bought it
because I suffer
from dry skin.
Please, you can't
cut me loose.
I mean, I-I can't go
to prison.
Unsanitary.
Not that
it's any of my business,
but it was straight before.
I know.
Oh, I get it.
Look less together.
Get underestimated.
[Chuckles]
You gotta wave
your hand slower.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
If you want soap, you just click
your heels together three times.
How do you think I'm planning
on getting that dryer to work?
You know, you think you wouldn't
have these problems,
considering what
you guys charge.
Oh, no, I don't work here.
- But you, uh--
- I used to.
You're Mike Ross.
And you're Logan Sanders.
Paper towel?
Don't mind if I do.
After you.
- Don't mind if I do.
- I see you two have met.
We have.
And don't underestimate him
because of his tie.
I have always estimated
that tie correctly.
Now, can we talk
about business?
Depends on what
you're proposing.
That you walk away.
That doesn't sound
like much of a deal.
Well, he forgot to add
the part where you walk away
$20 million richer.
Pure profit.
No risk.
Win-win.
[Clears throat]
All right.
Sounds good.
Guess I just have
one question.
What exactly are you going to do
with this company?
All due respect, I don't see
how that's any of your concern.
All due respect, you're the
one coming to me with an offer.
So if I say it's my concern,
it is.
Mike, you're asking about
a competitor's business plan.
And if he wants
to not be competitors,
then he needs to answer
my question.
Okay, I'll tell you.
I'm gonna do what anyone would
and sell it for parts.
[Chuckles]
No deal.
Okay, Mike.
You win.
Let's, uh,
make it 30 million.
You could make it
a billion, Logan,
and the answer is still
gonna be the same,
'cause I made a promise
to Walter Gillis
that I would fight
to keep his company alive.
And I don't think he's gonna
believe that cutting a deal
to sell his workers out
is keeping that promise.
I thought you said
he was smart.
I am, which I why I know
what's going on here.
What exactly is that?
No one ever
tells you no.
You're used to getting
what you want.
But that's gonna stop
right now.
You're right.
I do always get what I want.
I don't see how this time's
gonna be any different.
I'll tell you
how it's gonna be different.
This time you're talking about
something that I care about.
So if you think I'm gonna
step aside and let you do--
Yeah, I don't care
if you step aside or not.
When I see something I want,
I take it,
and then I do whatever the hell
I want with it.
And what I wanna do with
this company is strip it down,
flip it over--
Okay, that's enough.
No, no, no, let him talk.
I wanna hear this.
Keep going, Sanders.
No, I don't need to
because you know how this ends.
Yeah, I do, with me
and Walter Gillis on one side
and you crying to your daddy
on the other.
We're done.
You're right.
We are.
Listen, the next time I say
"Don't come to a meeting,"
don't come to a meeting.
He came at me
just as hard as--
I don't give a shit
what he did.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
- Where are you going?
- To get you this company.
- What are you talking about?
- Weren't you listening?
He just gave up
his weak spot.
Was that true
about Jenkins?
I don't even know
a Jenkins.
But I do know Todd's vein
wasn't bulging.
And, Louis, you were actually
pretty good in there.
Yeah, I was.
And so were you.
So we're in agreement.
Yeah, you don't
completely suck.
I just meant that
we should stick by Todd Smith.
That story was so ridiculous,
it just might be true.
Great, I'll call Felton
and make the recommendation.
[Stammering] Well, hold up.
You're gonna do what now?
Call my client?
Louis.
It may be your client,
but it's still my case.
Like hell it is, Jeff.
- Okay. Okay, you call.
- Oh, I plan to.
And when I do,
I'll be telling them
that Mr. Slippery Fingers
is no longer our problem.
Just one second ago,
you said you believed him.
Yeah, I also told you that
his story was so ridiculous
and nobody would believe it.
Well, then it's our job
to make them believe it, Louis,
or this guy could wind up
in prison.
He is not my concern, Jeff.
Felton Securities is.
[Mutters]
Walter Gillis knows
what he's doing.
Yeah, so do I.
He's letting your pension
go unfunded,
so he can hoard $1 billion.
No, that money is earmarked
for expansion into Asia,
and I believe
in Walter's vision.
You might, but do the workers
you represent?
You're acting
as if our fund is empty.
I'm acting
as if it's 40% full.
And let me guess,
you're gonna fill up the rest.
Someone else wants to acquire
Gillis' company
before we can make an offer.
If you vote to block it,
we will fully fund your pension
the day we take over.
You're talking about me
selling out my friend.
I'm talking
about $500 million.
And why can you fund it
and they can't?
Well, they can with half
that billion, but they won't.
Because like I said, he's
hoarding it for that pipe dream.
You're gonna take that billion
for yourselves.
Half.
The other half goes to you
and your union--
the men Walter Gillis
supposedly cares about.
Pete, this is gonna happen
whether it's me or someone else.
And someone else may not
give you the chance to do
what you were elected to do:
Protect your people.
Hey.
How'd your meeting
with Harvey go today?
I thought talking about work
was against the rules.
Mm, talking about work is.
Talking about our day isn't.
I mean, if we can't do that,
then we're letting the case
come between us, right?
My meeting with Harvey
went fine.
But you didn't take
the deal.
Because it wasn't
a good deal.
Fine.
Okay, what's the matter
with you?
What's the matter is that
I heard what happened.
- From him?
- No, from Donna.
But it could have been
from any of the 50 people
who saw the two of you
going at it.
- Rachel--
- Just tell me this.
Did you refuse the deal
because it wasn't good enough
or because it came from Logan?
You think I didn't take
this deal
because of your history
with this asshole?
Well, you did
just call him an asshole.
He's an asshole because he's
willing to decimate a company
just to put some money
in his pocket.
Look, I gave my word
to Walter Gillis.
That's what I told Harvey
and what I told Logan
and what I didn't think
I'd have to tell you.
I'm just saying, all of this
could have been over today.
You think I don't want this
to be over?
I do.
But I can't take that deal.
And we said we wouldn't let this
come between us.
So don't.
- Hi, Donna.
- Hey, Louis.
What can I do for you?
Oh, well, I just came in
to bring you this and this
and all of these.
Those are the last seven
Todd Smiths you evaluated.
- Donna--
- Seven.
And you didn't cut
one of them loose.
- You heard me and Malone.
- I did.
And you're cutting this guy
loose just to spite him.
That's ridiculous.
Okay, so this has nothing
to do with Malone?
Nothing.
Where'd you get that?
Come on.
You know where I got it.
Louis...
I know he took your dream.
[Scoffs]
I mean, she didn't even
consider me.
Just brings him in,
had me train him,
and gives him
the corner office.
Hey, did I ever tell you
about the time that I auditioned
for Hamlet in college?
Obviously, you played Ophelia.
No, Chrissy Kiff did.
I was her understudy,
and I was so jealous.
I found myself wishing that
something would happen to her,
that she would get sick
or she would twist an ankle.
And then, the day
before we closed...
Her father died.
Donna, that wasn't
your fault.
But I still felt horrible
and ashamed
'cause my jealousy had brought
out something really ugly in me.
And as you can tell,
I still regret that.
You know you've never
told me a story
about yourself
like that before.
I've never told anyone
that story before.
Louis, I know how badly
you wanted this.
But this is a man's life.
We won't cut him loose.
I'll tell Malone.
I'm proud of you, Louis.
Did you get an offer
to walk away from your takeover?
I did.
What was the offer?
$30 million.
And you turned it down?
What the hell is wrong with you?
They're gonna rip
the company apart.
I don't care if they wanna use
Walter Gillis' head
as a paperweight.
You said you wanted
a grand slam.
That offer is a double.
Well, I'd rather have a double
than nothing.
Look, I know
what I am doing here.
Do you?
Because they just
flipped the head of the union.
And without his vote,
we don't have shit.
- What?
- These guys play to win.
They just promised
$1/2-billion donation
to their pension fund.
And unless Walter Gillis is
gonna match it, we're done.
Yeah.
That's what I thought.
You get that $30 million,
or you find yourself
another job.
Donna,
did you need something?
No, but Louis does.
He was planning to pitch you
that he take on Jeff Malone
before you and Harvey
even met him.
He saw Woodall coming
before we did?
And if he won,
he was hoping that
that would mean name partner.
I empathize with that, Donna.
I do.
But I have to make decisions
based on what's best
for the firm.
And I'm not here
to change your mind,
but maybe if you did
something else for Louis--
Such as?
Giving him
the corner office.
You mean
Jeff Malone's office?
He could move to Louis'.
I appreciate
you letting me know about Louis,
but I'm not going
to do that.
Well, why not?
Jeff Malone just got here.
Because I said so.
Now if you'll excuse me--
You're sleeping with him.
- What?
- Of course.
That glow, the morning meetings,
you had Harvey take your lunch.
How could I miss it?
I'm losing my edge.
Donna, there is nothing
going on between--
you're not losing your edge.
But I ended my relationship
with Jeff Malone
the day that I hired him.
And I respect that.
But you said
you make decisions
based on what's best
for the firm.
Isn't giving Louis his dignity
back good for the firm?
Hey, I got your message.
Usually when someone
wants to talk business--
I want to take your offer.
Mike, that offer's gone.
And what if I told you
I'd take less?
I'd say I can't
give you less.
Come on, you're the guy
who settles.
I'm telling you
I wanna settle.
You're telling me
you have to settle.
And I know that
you can get that offer back.
It's not my job
to get it back.
And even if it was, you think
he's gonna give you a nickel
after what you said to him?
What I said to him?
What about what he said to me?
I don't care what he said
to you.
I gave you a way out,
and you insisted
on going to that meeting.
You didn't do that for me.
You did that for your client.
What difference does it make?
It was a win-goddamn-win.
And you shit all over it.
Now I'm saying,
I'll take it.
Yeah, well,
it doesn't work that way.
I'm here as a courtesy.
You're only here
because you lost.
- Harvey, I'm--
- Enough.
That company's fate is sealed.
It always has been.
And the next time you walk away
from the table,
be prepared to walk away
from the table.
Hmm.
Wanna pour me one of those?
Help yourself.
So what's going on
with Mike Ross?
How do you know I'm thinking
about Mike Ross?
Who else would it be?
He got you on the ropes?
No, I got him.
And he's about to go down.
How do you know?
'Cause the only way
to stay in the game
is to get Walter Gillis
to give up his dream.
And you don't think
he has the stomach
to rip off the arm
to save the body.
No, he doesn't.
You don't seem to feel good
about that.
No, I don't.
Harvey.
Do you remember when I gave you
the Collins case?
Yeah.
It was brutal,
what we had to do.
It was my first taste
of that kind of thing.
And you loved it.
What's your point?
Some people love
the taste of blood.
Other people, hmm.
Better to find out
who you are sooner than later.
You saying
I'm doing him a favor?
I'm saying,
you're being who you are
and letting him
be who he is.
What are you doing?
I'm just thinking
about how much
I'm going to miss
having my own office.
Put your pride away, okay?
You can still go back to Harvey.
I went back to Harvey.
The money's off the table.
Then you have to flip
that vote.
The only way to do that
is to get Walter Gillis
to put $500 million
into that pension fund.
And if he does that,
he loses his expansion.
Mike, then do it.
Amy, when his son died,
this company became his family.
If he doesn't expand, then
his company's gonna die too.
I ask him to do that,
then I'm no better than Logan.
No, you are better,
because after you do this,
you're still gonna fight
to keep them alive.
Gillis is not gonna see it
that way.
He's just gonna see
some slick banker
who sold him a bill of goods
just to end up doing
what everybody else
was at least up front about.
Mm.
Then why don't you
just pack up your shit
and crawl out of here with
your tail between your legs?
Because if you don't have
the stomach to handle this,
then you don't belong here.
Hey, uh,
got your message.
Is there something wrong
with Felton Securities?
Not at all.
Oh, thank God.
I just assumed since you wanted
to meet here in Malone's office.
Oh, this isn't his office
anymore.
Oh, did he get fired?
No, but he is moving.
Louis, I know it hasn't always
been easy for you
to embrace new partners,
but you've made
a great effort with Jeff.
[Laughs]
All in a day's work.
And your day's work has
benefited this firm for years.
So we thought it was time
to show you
a little
overdue appreciation.
[Chuckles]
This office?
I gave this office to Jeff
because I wanted him
to feel valued here.
But the truth is, I--
I should have given it to you.
[Stammers]
[Groans]
I don't know what to say.
Oh, okay.
All right, let it out.
[Sobbing]
No way.
Pete Kreeling would never side
with them.
He would, and he has,
because they offered
what you couldn't--
security for his workers.
They're my goddamn workers.
Then show them
that you care about them.
Fund the pension,
and fund it now.
You told me you'd fight
to keep this from happening.
I told you I would fight
to protect your company.
And right now, this is
the best way of doing that.
You're talking
about using my expansion money.
If you don't use it now,
there's gonna be
nothing to expand.
You son of a bitch,
you manipulated me.
No, I told you
a war was coming
and that you needed
a war chest.
Well, now is the time
to crack it open.
You told me what I wanted
to hear to get me on your side.
You're the same as them.
You're wrong.
I looked you in the eye,
and I told you that I wanted
to save your company.
They looked me in the eye
and told me they wanted
to rip it apart.
You're the same as them!
And you're an naive old man
having a tantrum
because he's not getting
his way!
That expansion
was my dream.
I know.
But now it's time to wake up.
Fund the pension, Walter.
Pete Kreeling's vote
stays in our favor, and...
We live to fight
another day.
No.
I just wanted to thank you,
you know, for the new office.
It's a downgrade.
Not to me.
I also wanted to thank you
for lunch.
- I didn't show up for lunch.
- I know.
You thought you were
sending me a message.
I was sending you a message.
Not the one you wanted,
Jessica.
You see,
because what I heard is that
you don't trust yourself
around me.
If I didn't,
I wouldn't have put you
right next door.
Jessica, say what you will,
but we both know
where this is headed--
you and me
watching these.
You think you know me
that well?
Well, if I don't,
I'm about to.
Neighbor.
More. More. More.
Ah, ah.
Thank you.
Happy corner office.
Open it.
- Is this...
- Me.
As Ophelia.
But I thought you--
Yeah, well,
sometimes bitter memories
become bittersweet
when you share them
with a friend.
- You here to pick up Rachel?
- No.
No, I just came by
to say thanks.
For what?
For not giving me
a way out.
You funded the pension.
100%.
You just got rid
of half your war chest.
Maybe, but I also did
what you thought I couldn't do.
I got the vote back.
Maybe now you'll realize that
I'm willing to go the distance.
All you did was make it
to round two.
Oh, so you thought
this was gonna be like
one of those early Tyson fights,
the ones that only lasted
45 seconds.
Remember what happened
the first time
someone made it
out of round one?
And what ever did happen
to Buster Douglas?
I don't know,
but wherever he is,
they can't take that title away
from him.
Hey.
What you working on?
You know what I'm working on.
You wanna go home?
[Cell phone vibrates]
Harvey.
Guess that means you're
gonna be working late, huh?
Um...
Thanks to the guy
we're up against.
He is proving to be much tougher
than everyone expected.
- Everyone?
- Not everyone.
He sounds like
a real douche bag.
[Laughs]
You know,
he's not that tough.
I can work on this tomorrow.
Let's get out of here.
You really gonna
work on that tomorrow?
No, I'm going to work on it
later tonight,
but at least I'll be home.
Think I can take a look at it
when you're done?
I think not.
Just a proofread?
Ah, still no.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man